飛馬
車輛準備區
總統前往家鄉巡回拉票備戰南卡初選
鄧巴下周二前往俄亥俄巡回拉票
約翰  我們雇你來洗車
John! We're paying you to clean cars,
不是讓你來看報的
not read the paper.
好的  抱歉
Yeah, okay. Sorry.
人人影視傾情奉獻
翻譯  章魚埃克斯
翻譯  草草
翻譯  吃貨丁小七
翻譯  癢癢惦記小跟班
翻譯  小暴徒
翻譯  江湖人稱王姑娘
翻譯  肉松
時間軸  行遠
顧問  老杜
后期  餓得慌
校對  草草
總監  草草
紙牌屋
第四季  第三集
每當我感念慈愛的天主
When I think of the goodness of Jesus
和他對我的恩典
and all that He's done for me,
我的靈魂都會大喊  哈利路亞
my soul shouts out, "Hallelujah."
-哈利路亞  -阿門
- Hallelujah! - Amen.
真是太動人了
That was absolutely beautiful.
你們唱得好聽又響亮
You sang it as heavenly and as loudly
不輸我們達拉斯  阿門
as we do in Dallas. Amen!
阿門
Amen.
我母親和我非常榮幸地
My mother and I are proud to
請出曾在國會為你們的權益奮戰
introduce a man who fought for you in Congress.
如今繼續在白宮為你們奮斗的人
He's fighting for you now in the White House.
我們希望能幫他留在白宮
We wanna help him to stay there.
-阿門  -阿門
- Amen. - Amen.
有請弗蘭克·安德伍德總統
President Frank Underwood!
歡迎
All right!
謝謝
Thank you.
你們唱得太好了
You're all wonderful.
謝謝大家  快請坐
Thank you. Please be seated.
這樣美好的上午  這樣和諧的教堂
You know, it's on a morning like this, in a church like yours,
讓我為做個南卡人驕傲
that I'm very proud to be a South Carolinian.
"你們有多少人開車來教堂的
"How many of you drove to church?
我先問各位一句
Let me start by asking,
今天早上你們有多少人是開車來的"
how many of you drove to church here this morning?"
你們今早有多少人是開車來教堂的
How many of you drove to get to church here this morning?
你們有多少人是拼車來的呢
And how many of you drove together?
我理解拼車的各位
Well, I can appreciate that.
這年頭的油價
Gas prices right now
快把大家都燒窮了
are putting a strain on everybody's pocketbooks.
你們說對不對
Isn't that true?
我想加夫尼的油價尤其高
I think maybe more here in Gaffney,
至少我對加夫尼尤其感同身受
at least I feel it here in Gaffney more than anywhere else.
"尤其是在加夫尼
"Especially here in Gaffney.
作為總統  我覺得對此負有責任
Now, as president, I feel responsible for that.
或許  我對這里的責任感更強烈
Or maybe, I feel even more so here.
我們這里向來就不怎么富裕
You know, we've never been a rich town.
我小的時候常常琢磨
You know, a lot of times in my childhood, I thought to myself,
'為什么我們這里在世人眼中就跟空氣似的呢
'Why, we just, we were almost like an invisible town to people...
我們無關緊要'"
We didn't matter.'"
我們無關緊要
That we didn't matter.
當然了  我還是個白人小子呢
And, of course, I was a white boy.
雖然我家挺窮的
And as poor as my family was,
但還是比在座的許多家庭寬裕不少
we still were a lot better off than a lot of your families...
你們不僅要和貧窮斗爭
who not only had to struggle through poverty
還得和種族歧視斗爭
but had to fight racism as well.
你們有多少人還記得1973年
Now, how many of you remember 1973?
"你們有多少人還記得1973年
"Now, how many of you remember 1973?
那年的汽油價格跟今天一樣飆漲
When gas prices were as bad as they are today,
我們為了加油  得排隊排好幾里地
and we had to wait hours just to fill our tank.
石油輸出國家組織當時想要挾我們
Why, OPEC was trying to hold us hostage then
就像今天  俄羅斯也想故技重施
just as Russia's trying to hold us hostage now.
但是不知怎地
But somehow...
我們這個小社區團結了起來  是不是
our little community, why, we came together, didn't we?
我們團結了起來  是不是"  是的
We came together, didn't we?" Yes.
我們互幫互助  同舟共濟
We looked out for each other. We were there for each other.
也許我們對國內其他地方無關緊要
Now, maybe we didn't matter to the rest of the country,
但我們對彼此卻至關重要
but we sure as heck mattered to each other.
我們還在和貧窮斗爭
We're still struggling with poverty,
我們仍然需要和種族歧視斗爭
and racism is still something we have to fight against.
但是我知道  這地方非常重要
But I know that this town does matter.
你們都非常重要
That all of you matter.
我這么說可不僅僅是因為非裔
And I don't just say that because African Americans
手里握著全州一半的選票
represent half the vote in this state.
我這么說是因為  盡管有種種問題
I say that because, despite our troubles...
我們仍然團結一體
we are one community.
我們仍是一家人
One family.
這給了我們力量
And that gives us strength.
這股力量無比強大
That strength is a powerful thing.
不容忽視
It's not invisible.
光芒萬丈
It radiates.
我相信上帝會給我目標
I place my faith in God to give me purpose.
我希望你們給我力量
I put my hope in you to give me strength.
嗯  先生
Yes, sir.
而明天你們投票的時候
And come tomorrow, when you vote...
我也希望你們能信任我
I hope that you will place your trust in me...
讓我們繼續帶領這個國家前行
...to help continue to lead this country
就像我們在這里齊心協力  共建家園
as we have led this community, together.
非常感謝你們
Thank you all very much.
早上好
Good morning.
我是莉安·哈維  去華盛頓
I'm LeAnn Harvey, traveling to Washington.
第一夫人還沒來  哈維女士
The First Lady isn't here yet, Ms. Harvey,
不過如果你愿意的話可以先登機
but you're welcome to board the plane, if you'd like.
不了  我還是等她來吧  謝謝
Uh, no, I'll wait until she gets here. Thank you.
艾丹
Aidan.
我剛把調研報告發過去了
Hey, I just sent the research.
-結果怎么樣  -遮天怒火啊
- What's the gist? - The anger, it's biblical.
-油價鬧的嗎  -是啊  上學燒汽油
- Uh, gas prices? - Yeah, gas is school.
上班燒汽油
Gas is work.
全家去迪士尼樂園也得燒汽油
Gas is the family trip to Disneyland.
油價每漲一毛錢  憤怒指數就漲6個百分點
Every cent it goes up is another six points on the anger index.
我們預測油價升至7元每加侖  就會全民暴動
We predict that $7 a gallon will get you riots.
第一夫人呢
What about the First Lady?
她的形象比她丈夫積極多了
Oh, she's faring better than he is.
主要是同情她母親病重
Sympathy for the sick mother.
多謝你們加急趕出來
Thanks for the rush job on this.
你是朋友嘛  再說這個要比
Well, you're a friend. And this is far more interesting than...
調查五歲小孩的抗抑郁藥名  或者
testing names of anti-depressants for five-year-olds, or...
中產家庭主婦垂涎什么顏色的跑步機有趣多了
what color cross trainers soccer moms will drool over.
-我還以為你討厭政治  -沒錯
- I thought you hated politics. - I do.
但是憤怒和誘惑
But anger? And seduction?
這些可好玩得很
Those are interesting.
-母親  我的耳環  -怎么
- Mother, my earrings. - Yes?
被你拿了
You took them.
我才沒拿
I did no such thing.
我說了不是我...
I said I don't...
你要拿我的錢  我也拿點你的東西
You're taking my money. I took something of yours.
克萊爾
Claire...
你今天走了就別回來了
When you leave today, I don't want you coming back.
我想來就來  想走就走  母親
Oh, I'll come and go as I please, Mother.
太滑稽了
This is unreal.
你確定我們能指望這人
You sure we can count on this guy?
他厭惡弗蘭西斯  這一點絕對可以指望
He loathes Francis. That we can count on.
但是你也多留意
But use your best judgment.
這是誰做的調查
Who compiled this?
和我有合作的一家分析公司
An analytics firm I contract with,
國內頂尖
one of the best in the country.
他們可靠嗎
They can be trusted?
可靠  我直接和老板接洽的
Yes. I work directly with the owner.
弗蘭西斯很需要拿下南卡羅萊納
Francis really needs this win in South Carolina.
當然了
He sure does.
再向市場投放些戰略儲備吧
Let's release more of the strategic reserve.
這也許能減緩漲價勢頭  但遏制不住的
That might slow down the price inflation, but it won't halt it.
兩位女士可喜歡這道肋排啊
How are you two ladies enjoying those ribs?
吃完之后我得美美地睡一會兒
Mmm, I'm gonna need a nap after this.
那你們慢用
Well, you'll have time.
我還得打兩小時的電話籌款
I have two hours of fundraising calls to make.
非常感謝您
It was very nice of you
讓我們在您家落腳  總統先生
to let us stay at your house, Mr. President.
我們加夫尼人就是這么好客
Well, that's how we do things here in Gaffney.
先生
Sir?
聽著  我決不會和他談救市計劃
Listen, I am not gonna negotiate a bailout
除非他在私有化問題上讓步
if he won't budge on privatization.
他想餓死自己的人民  隨他的便
If he wants to let his own people starve, so be it.
他或許會轉向北京求助  那樣就會
He may look for relief from Beijing, and that would--
他恨中國勝過恨我們
The only thing he hates more than us is China.
他不會對北京扣頭的
He won't kowtow.
但如果佩特羅夫真向北京低頭
But if Petrov does cave to them,
那全球能源市場就會...
that puts the global energy--
凱茜  我待會兒再打給你
Look, Cathy, I have to call you back.
-什么時候  -半小時前吧
- When? - About 30 minutes ago.
-這是您的保險柜  433號  -謝謝
- So this will be your box, number 433. - Thank you.
您要不再在我們這里再開個儲蓄賬戶
Would you like to open up a savings account with us?
-借記卡什么的  -不了  保險箱就好
- Debit card? - No, the box is fine.
好吧
Okay.
我能不能自己...
Would you mind if I...
當然可以  我回避一下
Oh, sure. I'll give you some privacy.
謝謝啦
Thank you.
很高興見到你
Good to see you.
我也是  弗蘭西斯
You, too, Francis.
真沒想到
I'm surprised.
一直沒你的消息  然后你突然就來了
I don't hear from you, then you just show up.
說實話  直到飛機落地  我都不確定要不要來
Mmm, to be honest, I wasn't sure until I landed.
你有點曬黑了
You've gotten some sun.
昨天去田間地頭拉票來著  該戴頂帽子的
Tractor-pulling event yesterday. I should've worn a hat.
-桃瑞絲和西莉婭也在嗎  -來過
- Are Doris and Celia here? - They were.
我在客房里為她們加了兩張床
I set up cots for them in the guest room,
但我一聽你要來  就讓她們住酒店去了
but when I heard you were coming, I sent them off to a hotel.
我想著你可能會想住客房
I figured you'd want that room for yourself.
多謝你費心了
That's very thoughtful.
你馬上還有活動吧
You have an event now.
萊姆斯頓學院
Limestone College.
那我和你一起去
Well, I'll join you.
她們也會去  如果你不想見...
They'll be there, if you'd rather not see--
沒事
It'll be fine.
除非你不想讓我去
Unless you'd rather I not go.
怎么會  我很樂意你一起去
No, I'd love you to come.
如果他知道跟我有關
If he knows I'm involved...
那就別讓他知道
So make sure he doesn't.
我能看看嗎
Can I see it?
我的天
Oh, boy.
這下有好戲看了
Now, this could get interesting.
明早之前辦好
We need it done by tomorrow morning.
我表親有個朋友  開了家工業打印店
Well, my cousin has a friend, owns an industrial print shop,
但這么大幅的
but a job that size...
這些應該夠了
This should cover it.
綽綽有余
And then some.
想不到希瑟·鄧巴也會玩這一套
Oh, I didn't know Heather Dunbar had it in her.
認識你很高興  蔡斯先生
It's nice to meet you, Mr. Chase.
真不喝點冰茶嗎
Well, are you sure you wouldn't like some iced tea?
謝謝  不喝了  我還有事
Thank you, no. I should get going.
要不留下玩玩吧
How about some fries with that shake?
照我說的把事情辦好  別讓我再跑一趟了
Get done what I want done. Don't make me come back here.
-曼尼怎么說的  -我代你的班  哥們
- What did Manny say? - I got your shift, bro.
-那車呢  -那輛蒙迪歐
- What about the car? - The Fusion.
我可以重設里程表
I can reset the odometer,
下班之后停到你家門口
park it in front of your place after work.
不過  你明晚之前必須還回來
But, hey... you gotta get it back by tomorrow night.
-不然等他們清點庫存...  -我保證
- Otherwise, when they do the inventory-- - I promise you.
好吧
All right.
說說報酬吧
So the cost.
等我工資發下來我就...
As soon as I get my paycheck, I'll--
不  我不想要錢
No. I don't want money.
其他在這兒干活兒的人我都看不上眼
Most of the other guys work here, they ain't much to look at.
但你
You?
我怎么都看不夠
Keep lookin' over.
哥們  你別...
Hey, man, listen...
-你還想不想用車  -我自己想辦法吧
- You want the car or not? - I'll find some other way.
我知道你的底細
I know about you.
我見過你的假釋官來查你的崗
I seen your parole officer come check in on you.
如果他知道你偷了一輛車  會怎么辦你
What would he say about you taking one of these cars?
來吧
Come on.
上車
Get in.
我今天剛剛了解到  萊姆斯頓學院
I just learned today that Limestone College,
創立于1845年
founded in 1845,
是南卡羅萊納第一所招收女生的學校
was the first women's college in South Carolina,
在全國也是最早的幾所之一
and one of the first in the nation.
這非常了不起
And that's something to be proud of.
自那時起  這所學校和她的學生成就斐然
And since then, this school and its students have flourished.
這個年輕向上的群體
A young, eager community
超越種族  性別和背景
of men and women of all races and backgrounds,
是美國未來的最佳寫照
a true reflection of America's future.
他是怎么說服你回來的
How did he convince you to come back?
我自己說服了自己
I convinced myself.
我丈夫去世時我們結婚已有46年
Forty-six years I was married to my husband before he passed.
但如果他像弗蘭克對你那樣對我
But if he'd pulled on me what Frank pulled on you,
他會早死很多年
he would've been long gone.
我認為這樣對大家都有好處
I think it's worked out for the best.
您女兒將會是一位出色的眾議員
Your daughter is going to make a fabulous congresswoman.
謝謝
Well, thank you.
還有兩分鐘
Two minutes.
弗蘭克·安德伍德了解我們對平等的渴求
Now, Frank Underwood understands the need for equality,
無論是教育平等  還是生活中的平等
in education and throughout our lives.
最重要的是  他相信給每個美國人
Most of all, he believes in giving every American
謀生計的機會
the opportunity to earn a living.
他以前就踐行了這一信念  他也會堅持下去
He put this belief into action before and he will again,
弗蘭克·安德伍德
and Frank Underwood
決不會允許他的奮斗止步于萊姆斯頓
will not allow this journey to end with Limestone.
你們將步入世界
You will go out into this world
讓世人驚艷于你們的才智
and astonish us all with your intellect,
你們的價值  和你們的力量
your... your worthiness, and your strength.
現在請允許我請出我見過的最堅強的女人
Now, I would like to introduce two of the strongest women I know.
你們倆真是  親密無間啊
Well, don't you look thick as thieves.
以及美國的第一夫人  克萊爾·安德伍德
...and the First Lady of the United States, Claire Underwood.
就好像她從沒離開過
It's as though she never left.
我擔心的就是這個
And that's what I'm afraid of.
來吧  我們盡快干完
All right, let's hurry on up, now.
布加耶夫告訴我他們愿意
Bugayev is telling me that they are willing
在下月1日之前
to reduce their oil output by
再減產20%的原油
another 20% by the first of next month.
油價走勢預測如何
What are the projections on gas prices?
每桶原油超過150美元
North of 150 a barrel for oil.
汽油每加侖6到7塊
Six, maybe $7 a gallon for fuel.
我的電話都快被打爆了  先生
My phone has been ringing off the hook, sir,
從英國到波蘭都打個不停
from the U.K. to Poland.
國際貨幣基金組織希望
The IMF wants to help us
幫助我們制定債務免除方案
with the debt relief solution.
先生
Sir?
我們得以暴制暴
We need to respond to strength with strength.
我不知道我們還要怎么"暴"
Well, I don't know how we could be any stronger,
除非入侵俄羅斯
other than to invade Russia.
如果我們那么做了呢
And what if we do?
-什么  先生  -不是動用軍隊
- Excuse me, sir? - Not with troops.
而是用恐懼
With fear.
他從未信任過我們
He's never trusted us.
他已經覺得我們操縱了米爾金失敗的政變
He already thinks we're behind Milkin's failed coup.
如果我們讓米爾金有機會取得成功呢
What if we put Milkin in a position to succeed.
我并不在乎米爾金是不是真能成功
Now, I don't care if Milkin actually succeeds.
解凍他一切財產  讓他飛去接壤國家
Unfreeze all his assets. Fly him to a border country.
讓他跟其他異見者見面
Put him in a room with other dissidents.
得讓佩特羅夫知道我們不會罷休
Petrov needs to know that we'll stop at nothing.
先生  這樣的行為將造成外交影響...
Sir, the diplomatic repercussions of such an action--
我只想裝裝樣子
All I want is the appearance.
盡快估計一下最好和最壞的結果
Let's look at best and worst case scenarios as soon as possible.
多謝了
Thank you very much.
抱歉  我以為
Oh, I'm sorry. I thought you were--
那床太硬了
That bed was too stiff.
-那我過去睡吧  -就睡這兒吧
- I'll sleep in there then. - Sleep in here.
我們以前在地板上鋪床墊
We had the mattress on the floor.
什么
What?
頭一年  床墊還有邦邦硬的枕頭
That first year, the mattress and those lumpy pillows.
你大半夜還老偷我的
Which you used to steal from me in the middle of the night.
還不是因為你把被子都拽走了
Well, because you would hog all the covers.
天吶  我們當時過得真夠差的
God, we were living like heathens.
那是因為我們把一切都投入了競選
Well, because we were spending everything we had on the race.
但我記得我以前把這里想作宮殿
I remember I used to think this place was a palace, though.
-這里是座宮殿  -跟農場沒法比
- It was. - Not compared to the ranch.
是座宮殿  是因為它屬于我們
Well, it was a palace because it was ours.
晚安  弗蘭西斯
Good night, Francis.
安德伍德2016
媒體都包圍了房子
The press has surrounded the house.
我根本出不去
I can't leave the damn place
得先想好我究竟該說什么
until I know exactly what I'm gonna say.
我們得取消您的活動
We need to cancel your events.
當然得取消了
Of course we need to cancel my events.
-我臉上的表情...  -怎么回事
- The expression on my face is a-- - What's going on?
...拍攝地點未知
...taken in a nondescript location,
似乎并非是直接對三K黨的支持
does not seem to be a direct endorsement for the KKK.
-天吶  -我父親
- My God. - My father.
先生  瓊斯議員女士要回德州了
Sir? Congresswoman Jones is heading back to Texas.
馬上給我接通她的電話
Get her on the phone for me, right now.
密查姆  你得去幫我個忙
Meechum, I need you to do me a favor.
現在尚不清楚
There are no clues at the moment
此事是誰所為
as to who may be responsible,
損壞公物行為將安德伍德與三K黨聯系了起來
南卡羅來納州  加夫尼
加夫尼警察正在取下照片
but Gaffney PD is taking the canvas picture down
一小時內就能完成  以備進一步調查
within the hour for further examination.
就在初選這天
On primary day.
我現在無法證實任何事  那是誰
I can't verify anything yet in terms of who it is,
或者照片是否是真
or even whether it's real, or--
新罕布什爾前一天  是婚姻問題的報道
The day before New Hampshire, there's a marriage story,
現在在南卡羅來納又鬧這事
and now in South Carolina we have this?
我們為什么會遭偷襲
Uh, how are we getting blindsided?
-我該接一下  -讓它響去吧
- I should get that-- - Let it ring.
聽著
Look...
吵架的事還是你告訴我我才知道
I didn't even know about the fight until you told me.
你怎么能指望我知道照片的事
And how was I supposed to know about this photo?
因為預防這種爛事就是你的職責
Because it is your job to get out ahead of this shit.
這事該是對手研究團隊去挖  競選就是如此
The oppo team should've tracked this down. That's the campaign.
如果沃恩不知道  或是如果總統沒告訴他
So, if Vaughn didn't know, or the president didn't tell him...
肯定是他身邊的人  能掌握很多情況的人
It has to be somebody close to him. Someone with a lot of access.
總統打來了
The president's on the line.
先生  是道格  賽斯也在
Sir, it's Doug. I'm in here with Seth.
我要說實話  我要說那是我父親
I'm gonna tell the truth. I'm gonna say it is my father.
如果能說得好
That's probably the best response,
這樣回應或許最好
if you have a good way to frame it.
我知道該說什么  問題是在哪說
I know what to say. The question is where.
一對一  獨家采訪
One-on-one. Something exclusive.
不能跟媒體說
Not in front of the media.
我得直接對選民說
I need to connect directly to the voters,
非裔選民
the African American voters.
總統先生  國務卿打來了
Mr. President, I've got the Secretary of State.
我回頭再打過去
I'll call her back.
稍等  密查姆
Hang on, boys. Meechum?
還在這兒  先生
It's here, sir.
你都了解到了什么
What can you tell me?
昨天  一個叫萊斯利·麥金泰爾的女人
Yesterday, a woman named Leslie McIntyre
開了個新保險箱
opened a new box.
我正在查這個名字
I'm having the name run now,
但她似乎用了假社保號
but it looks like she used a fake social.
監控錄像呢
What about security footage?
他們每天早上重置攝像頭
They reset the cameras every morning.
我問了她長什么樣
I asked what she looked like
經理只說是個白人黑發女人
and all the manager said is that it was a Caucasian brunette.
沒什么異常之處
Nothing strange about her.
好吧  把盒子拿回來
All right. Bring the box back here.
一刻別讓它離開你的視線范圍
Don't let it out of your sight.
就我所知  只有一張照片
As far as I know, there's only one photograph.
密查姆說照片還在銀行
Meechum says it's still at the bank.
先生  是我一個人了
Sir, it's just me.
你跟我想到一起了嗎
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
你盯住他
Well, you keep an eye on him.
我要白宮所有人的郵件和電話記錄
I want emails and phone records of everyone in the White House.
包括你的
Including yours.
我的  你真覺得...
Mine? You honestly think--
有什么問題嗎
Is there a problem?
沒有
No.
很好
Good.
真是不幸
It's unfortunate.
鄧巴女士  鄧巴女士
Ms. Dunbar! Ms. Dunbar? Ms. Dunbar?
鄧巴對"安德伍德2016"照片做出回應
這樣的畫面
The imagery...
居然有人靠如此卑劣的手段
That anyone would try to inflame racial discord
企圖煽動種族不和
by doing something so base.
那是不是凱文·安德伍德根本不重要
Whether it's Calvin Underwood isn't the point.
即便是  這一點我們無法確認
If it is, and we have no confirmation on that,
那么是誰掛上去的  為什么要這么做
I mean... Who put this up? And why?
誰知道呢
Who knows.
而且父親的罪未必是孩子的罪
And the sins of the father aren't necessarily the sins of the son.
但  這令人不安  十分不安
But... it's troubling. Very troubling.
這樣的伎倆很可能揭開舊瘡疤
Stunts like these have the potential to open old wounds.
我們不能允許那樣的事發生  我們得不受其影響
We can't let that happen. We need to rise above it.
要明白  不管你支持誰
Make clear, no matter who you support,
這樣的行為是不可容忍的
that this sort of behavior will not be tolerated.
給我接克拉克牧師和吉恩·克蘭希
Get me Reverend Clark and Gene Clancy on the phone.
他們要你去大巴那邊
Hey, they want you out by the bus.
大巴那邊
By the bus?
-你是誰  -抱歉
- Um, who are you? - Sorry.
巴特勒縣辦公室的馬克
Mark from the Butler County office.
他們要辛辛那提的志愿者
They want all the Cincinnati volunteers
都去大巴那邊集合跟鄧巴合影
to gather by the bus for a photo with Dunbar.
珍告訴我我不能離開崗位的
Jenn told me I wasn't supposed to leave--
所以她叫我過來喊你
That's why she sent me.
她不希望你錯過合影  去吧
She didn't want you to miss the photo. Go.
大巴那邊嗎
Out by the bus?
她叫我替你
She told me to cover for you.
好
Okay, um...
有幾個人沒來
well, there were a couple of no-shows,
其他人都來了
but, you know, otherwise, everyone's here.
-好  謝謝  -太棒了  謝謝
- Okay. Thanks. - Very convenient. Thanks.
快去吧
Enjoy.
我是《克利夫蘭老實人報》的戴維·格里姆斯
I'm David Grimes with the Cleveland Plain Dealer.
你的證件呢
Where's your credential?
我蠢得把證件忘在車里了
I was an idiot and left it in the car.
不過前臺簽到處的人認識我
They recognized me at the check-in desk, though.
我可以帶你去等候處
I can direct you to the bullpen,
但是這一區不對媒體開放
but this area is off-limits to the press.
我其實是來采訪辛西婭·德里斯科爾的
I'm actually supposed to do an interview with Cynthia Driscoll.
先遣人員叫我來這邊
The Advance guys said I should come this way.
在這里等一下
Wait here.
抱歉  總統先生  我們做不到
I'm sorry, Mr. President, we just can't do it.
這里45%的選票在非裔手中
Forty-five percent of the vote here is African American.
你和你母親對我的支持
You and your mother standing by my side
會有很重要的作用...
would go a long way to put this--
我在一個非裔及拉丁裔的選區競選議員
I am running for Congress in a black and Latino district.
我母親曾在游行時被暴打  被水沖
My mother was beaten and hosed down in marches.
你想讓我們替一個三K黨人的兒子作擔保嗎
You want us to vouch for a man whose father was in the KKK?
-不  他不是三K黨  -照片上那個就是他
- No, he was not in the Klan. - That was him in that picture.
對  可這個我已經解釋過了
Yes, but I've explained that.
內戰就是在本州掀起的
This is the state where the Civil War started,
有些人汽車保險杠上還貼著南軍旗貼紙
where you can still see rebel flags on bumper stickers.
這里曾有很嚴重的種族暴行  總統先生
There is a history of racist brutality here, Mr. President.
那種符號影響很大
Those sort of symbols matter.
能讓你母親接電話嗎
Could you put your mother on, please?
媽媽
Mom?
他想跟你說話
He wants to speak to you.
總統先生
Mr. President.
聽著  我們需要團結  我為西莉婭背書了
Listen, we need to stand together. Now, I've endorsed Celia.
克萊爾在德州能給她幫很大忙
Claire can do a great deal for her in Texas.
現在遠離安德伍德一家對她更好
She's better off without the Underwoods at this point.
那你的診所呢
But what about your clinic?
你要是拿我們的診所要挾我  別人會怎么看
Imagine how that would look, holding our clinic for ransom.
我是想博取您的好意  議員女士
I'm appealing to your goodwill, Congresswoman.
等我們不再遭受毆打和槍擊
When we stop getting beaten and shot...
我會好意待您的  總統先生
you'll have my goodwill, Mr. President.
再見
Goodbye.
再接吉恩·克蘭希
Get me Gene Clancy again.
會不會是奧林·蔡斯  弗蘭西斯
What if it's Oren Chase, Francis?
他也可能拿到一份副本
He could've gotten his hands on a copy.
照片可能不止一張
There may be more than one.
先打給密查姆  然后克蘭希
Meechum first, then Clancy.
盧卡斯
Lucas?
我們得談談
We need to talk.
-我還以為你...  -是的  不過已經出來了
- I thought you were--  - I was. I'm... I'm out now.
這很重要
This is important.
總統先生  您父親是種族主義者嗎
Mr. President, was your father a racist?
您父親是種族主義者嗎
Was your father a racist?
安德伍德夫人  你母親還好嗎
Mrs. Underwood, is your mother okay?
總統先生
Mr. President!
-蔡斯先生  -你是誰
- Mr. Chase? - Who are you?
特勤局的
United States Secret Service.
我們要的不是你  蔡斯先生
We're not after you, Mr. Chase.
我們是想要指使你這么干的人
We're after whoever put you up to it.
指使我做什么
Put me up to what?
你可以現在回答我
You can answer me here,
或者我們可以去問哥倫比亞辦事處
or we can go to the Columbia field office for questioning.
我不知道你在說什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
請您跟我來一下  先生
All right, I need you to come with me, sir.
-等等  -請出來  先生
- Now, hold on. - Step outside, sir.
我要找律師
I wanna talk to a lawyer.
4126號需要支援
I need backup at 4126.
-沒必要這樣吧  -除非你合作  先生
- Come on, that's not necessary. - Not if you cooperate, sir.
我告訴你不會惹麻煩吧
If I talk to you, I won't get in trouble?
我向上帝起誓  鄧巴女士  這都是真的
I swear to God, Ms. Dunbar. It's all true.
證據呢
Then where's the proof?
我沒辦法找證據  但你可以
I don't have the means, but you do.
你調查過他  你知道他很危險
You've investigated him before. You know he's dangerous.
古德溫先生
Mr. Goodwin--
如果我不是查到了真相  他為什么要針對我
Why would he go after me if I wasn't onto something?
這是一起高級釣魚執法
This was a high-level sting operation.
為此調動了大量資源
Major resources were dedicated to it.
我原本是個記者  沒有犯罪記錄
I'm... I was a journalist, no criminal record.
怎么突然就成了威脅  除非我...
How am I suddenly such a threat, unless I'm--
就算我相信你
Even if I did believe you,
我已經不是司法部的了  現在只是個普通市民
I am no longer part of the DOJ. I am a private citizen now.
正在競選總統
Who's running for president--
你來這兒不違反證人保護計劃的規定嗎
Aren't you breaking WITSEC protocol by being here?
我不想再跟他談了
I am no longer comfortable with this.
你是我最后的機會  求你了
You're... you're my last chance. Please!
-我建議你還是回家吧  -我  可是我
- I suggest that you go back home. - I'm... The things I've--
-別逼我們叫保安  -求你了  就
- Don't make us get security involved.  - Please. Just--
你得在這兒等五分鐘  讓她先離開
Just give us five minutes until she's out of the building.
求你了  求你聽我說
Please. Please listen to me.
我求你了
I'm... I'm begging you.
幫幫我
Just help me...
Help.
求你了  求你了
Please, please...
天吶
Oh, God...
你怎么能讓我跟他見面
How could you put me in a room with him?
我并不知道他想要說什么
I didn't know what he was gonna say.
不過我以為他這么煞費苦心
But I assumed that if he went to such great lengths--
他只有酒駕的證據  那什么都不算上
The DUI, that's all he has proof of. That's nothing.
我都幫過別人逃脫酒駕的懲罰
Even I have helped people get off for that.
-還有外遇  -沒證據
- There's the affair... - With no evidence.
他又扯什么謀殺  還殺了兩個
Then he leaps to murder... Two murders?
這人有病
The man is troubled.
他那眼神我們都看見了
We saw the look in his eye.
我以為他有什么真憑實據呢
I thought he might have something real.
他以前做編輯做得挺好的
He used to be a good editor.
可他現在是個定了罪的重犯
And now he is a convicted felon.
你說要想盡一切辦法的
You said no stone unturned.
對不起  我應該想得更周到一些的
I'm sorry, I should have thought better of it.
是啊  你是應該
Yes, you should have.
就這樣吧  我們在南卡羅來納情況如何
Let's let it go. How are we doing in South Carolina?
早期出口民調結果不錯
Early exit polls are good.
-我們有機會贏  -真能贏嗎
- We have a shot at winning. - Actually winning?
那個廣告牌造成了不小的破壞
That billboard's done real damage.
你能這么做我很感激  吉恩
I appreciate you doing this, Gene.
你真是救了我一命
You're really saving my life here.
等我競選縣長的時候你記著就行
Just remember it when I run for county executive.
你隨時需要我隨時過來
I'll be down here whenever you need me.
重點不在時間  而是給什么和給多少
Oh, it's not the when, it's the what. And how much.
下午好  奧林
Afternoon, Oren.
-總統先生  -坐吧
- Mr. President. - Have a seat.
上次大桃子的事你還沒長記性啊
Didn't you learn your lesson with all that Peachoid nonsense?
你說了要幫我搞定第4選區的
Well, you promised to help me with the 4th.
我被怨恨蒙蔽了
I let my bitterness get the better of me.
誰找的你  一個女的嗎
Who specifically approached you? A woman?
-黑頭發  -對
- Brunette?  - Yeah.
大概這么高  挺好看的
Uh, about so tall, good-looking.
也不告訴我名字
Wouldn't give me her name.
我們應該把所有的
We should get photos
鄧巴團隊里符合描述的人的照片找來
of everyone in Dunbar's staff that fits that description.
已經在整理了  夫人
Already compiling it, ma'am.
至于你嘛
And as for you...
你要去上電視  越多越好
you're gonna plant yourself in front of as many TV cameras
愿意拍你的都去上
that can gather around that bony ass of yours.
你要表現出萬分愧疚  然后良心發現
You're gonna be wracked with guilt and overcome with conscience.
你做好了  我就確保你不會被起訴
And you do that and I'll make sure that you aren't charged.
你想讓我說是鄧巴指使的嗎
You want me to say it was Dunbar?
拜托  聰明點  奧林  她會告你誹謗的
Come on, be smarter than that, Oren. She'll sue you for slander.
說你被收買了就行
Just say you were bought
剩下的大家自己就能琢磨出來
and people will connect the dots on their own.
把他帶走吧
Get him out of here.
我希望你不會像
I hope you don't Welsh on
對待奧林那樣違背對我的諾言
your promise to me the way you did with Oren.
你是家人  吉恩  我決不會背叛家人
You're family, Gene. I would never betray one of the family.
走吧
Shall we?
準備好了嗎
Ready?
你們很多人曾選我當市長
Many of you voted for me for mayor
是因為你們認識我一輩子了
because you've known me your whole lives.
而我認識弗蘭克·安德伍德一輩子了
Well, I've known Frank Underwood my whole life.
他是我的朋友  我信任他
He's my friend and I trust him,
我不在乎那個廣告牌上掛了什么
and I don't care what's on that billboard.
我為他是我的總統感到自豪
I'm proud he's my president,
我也為今天能同他站在一起而自豪
and I'm proud to have... be standing with him here today.
謝謝  吉恩
Thank you, Gene.
昨天  我站在這個教堂里
Yesterday, I stood in this church...
我提到了我們這個群體
and I talked about community.
我提到了我們集體的力量
I talked about our collective strength,
無論是黑人還是白人  在危機時刻走到一起
black and white, coming together during times of crisis.
今天肯定有很多人覺得我是個偽君子
And today there's probably a lot of you who think I'm a hypocrite.
一個父親是三K黨的人  怎么可能站在這里
How can a man whose father was in the KKK stand up here
真心實意地說出那些話呢
and mean the things he said?
沒錯  照片上的人是我父親
Yes, that is my father in that photograph,
我不會否認
I'm not going to deny it.
但事實是  他不是三K黨的人
But the truth is he wasn't in the Klan.
拍照片的那年
The year that photo was taken,
我父親需要五千美元償還債務
my father needed $5,000 to pay off our debts,
不然銀行就要沒收我們的農場
or the bank was gonna foreclose on our farm.
父親跑遍了這附近
Now, my father went to every other bank
方圓百里內的所有銀行
within a hundred miles of here,
沒一個愿意貸款給他
and no one would give him a loan.
他向朋友  向親戚借
He asked friends, he asked family,
但沒人有那么多錢
but nobody had that kind of money.
我們馬上就要傾家蕩產了
And we were about to lose everything.
當時  加夫尼第一銀行的行長
Now, at the time, the owner of the Gaffney First Bank
是三K黨的成員
was a member of the Klan.
這在座的一些人知道
Some of you know that.
他完全聽從三K黨的指揮
And he would do whatever the Klan told him to do,
我父親也清楚這一點
and my father knew that.
所以父親就做了他不得不做的
So my father did what he had to do.
他參加了一次集會并乞求那個分會的頭頭
He went to a meeting and begged the leader of that chapter
在銀行行長面前說句話
to talk to the owner of the bank.
照片就是拍攝于那次集會
And at that meeting, that's when that photograph was taken.
他出現在那里僅僅是為了挽救我們的農場
The only reason he was there was to try to save our farm.
凱文·安德伍德痛恨自己參加了那次會議
Now, Calvin Underwood hated himself for going to that meeting.
也痛恨自己拍下了那張照片
He hated himself for taking that photograph.
但會讓他更痛恨自己的  是不能保住我們的農場
But he would've hated himself even more if he'd lost our farm...
是不能養活自己的家人
if he hadn't been able to provide and support his family.
我不會試著讓你們原諒他
Now, look, I'm not trying to ask you to forgive him
出現在那張照片中
being in that photograph.
他大概以為永遠不會有人看到這照片
He probably thought no one would ever see it.
但我懇請大家同情他的困境
But I am asking you to empathize with his predicament.
并捫心自問...
And ask yourselves...
你們會為挽救自己的家庭做些什么
what would you do to save your family?
那盜取了照片  破壞了廣告牌的人
Now, whoever stole that photograph and vandalized that billboard,
他們的目的不是要揭露關于我過去的重大丑聞
they're not trying to unearth some big scandal about my past,
因為真相并非如此
'cause it just isn't true.
他們的目的是讓我們分裂
What they're trying to do is divide us.
他們真正要達到的目的
What they really wanna succeed in doing
是確保大家今天不把票投給我
is making sure you don't vote for me today.
他們為玷污我的形象
They've gone to a whole lot of trouble
真是煞費苦心
to make me look pretty bad.
但這就是政治
But that's politics.
我今天來到這里
My hope in coming here today...
開誠布公地對這件事發表聲明  是希望
and speaking openly and honestly about this...
我們能夠保持團結
is that we can stay united.
因此我打算一直待在這里
So my plan is to stay here as long as it takes,
跟每一個人單獨交談
to speak to each one of you individually,
解答你們所有的疑問
and answer every question that you might have.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
非常感謝  女士
Thank you very much, ma'am.
安德伍德總統
President Underwood,
在他家鄉南卡羅來納州加夫尼發表現場講話
speaking live in his home town of Gaffney, South Carolina,
回應稱其父
addressing claims that
是三K黨成員的言論
his father was a member of the Ku Klux Klan.
昨晚當地一塊公告牌遭到破壞
A billboard there was vandalized late last night
被掛上了一張總統父親站在一名
with a photo of his father standing
身著三K黨長袍的男子旁邊的照片
next to a man in Klan robes
并配文  "安德伍德2016"
with the caption, "Underwood 2016."
正如我們剛剛所看到的  總統沒有否認
As we've just seen, the president did not deny allegations
總統對三K黨公告牌一事作出回應
其父親與該組織有聯系的指控
that his father had some connection to the organization,
反而解釋說凱文·安德伍德只參加了一次集會
instead explaining that Calvin Underwood attended one meeting
是為避免家族桃園遭沒收  不得已而為之
as a last resort to save his family's peach farm from foreclosure.
今早其家人被指與三K黨
The president was subject to widespread criticism
有關聯的消息一經傳出  總統便飽受批評
after news of his family's alleged Klan connection broke this morning.
今天的初選結果將會...
Today's primary result will show--
我不知道她的名字  我問過  但她沒說
I don't know her name. I asked, but she wouldn't tell me.
奧林·蔡斯承認破壞廣告牌
我深感懊悔
And I deeply regret
我讓我的政治傾向影響了判斷力
that I allowed my political leanings to compromise my better judgment.
我想對可能侵犯到的人道歉
I want to apologize to anyone I might have offended
抱歉翻出了如此痛苦的畫面
by hoisting up such painful imagery.
有人打電話問是不是我們做的
We're getting calls asking if it was us.
-你覺得是我們團隊的人嗎  -絕對不會
- Do you think someone from our team-- - Absolutely not.
我覺得是安德伍德叫他這么說的
I think Underwood put this guy up to it.
他想反過來坑我們
He's trying to turn this back around on us.
我們必須堅決否認
We need to deny, forcefully.
我已經在下一場活動安排了媒體采訪
I'm already putting a press avail together at your next event.
可能我們得再考慮一下古德溫了
Maybe we need to reconsider Goodwin.
-你怎么想的  -我也不確定
- What do you have in mind? - I'm not sure.
看這個
Look at this.
是從白宮泄露的
It came from the goddamn White House!
我們在訊問攝影師了  先生
We're questioning the photographer now, sir.
我準備好了聲明
I've got a statement prepared that
這只是個普通活動
this was a run-of-the-mill event,
您和許多參與內戰重演的演員合過影
that you took photos with lots of re-enactors.
你怎么解釋都沒用
It doesn't matter how you spin it.
我剛剛在教堂
I just stood in front of
對一群非裔發表講話
a group of African Americans in a church
請他們相信我
asking them to believe in me.
他們看到我父親和三K黨人并立已夠糟了
It's bad enough they see my father next to a Klansman.
現在又看到我和奴隸制的象征站在一起
Now they see me next to a symbol of slavery.
我要查出是誰泄露的
I wanna find out who's leaking this shit,
把他的頭釘在木樁上
and I want their head on a goddamn stake!
先生  我有個想法
Sir, I have a theory.
我覺得...
I think...
我覺得可能是艾德華·密查姆
Well, I think it might be Edward Meechum.
密查姆
Meechum?
他知道您和第一夫人發生了爭吵
He knew about the argument between you and the First Lady.
弗吉尼亞那次他也跟去了
He was there on that trip to Virginia.
他絕不會做出這種事來
He would never do something like this.
鄧巴有很多錢
Dunbar has a lot of money.
向各大電視臺發布聲明
Put out a statement to the networks
我不會發表落選講話了
that I won't be giving a concession speech.
先生  您不覺得這樣看起來像在逃避
Sir... don't you think that might look like you're running from--
我剛剛輸了我的家鄉
I just lost my home state.
我不想再折騰我自己了
I'm not gonna rake myself over the coals.
密查姆
Meechum?
我不能排除任何人
I'm not ruling anyone out.
先生
Sir?
我把銀行保險箱拿來了
I brought the safety deposit box for you.
放下吧
You can put it down.
-密查姆  -是  先生
- Meechum. - Yes, sir?
我有沒有給過你任何傷害我的理由
Have I given you any reason to hurt me?
傷害您  先生
Hurt you, sir?
我有沒有過對不起你的時候
Have I done you wrong in any way?
抱歉  先生  我不明白
I'm sorry, sir, I don't understand.
看著我的眼睛  密查姆
Look me in the eyes, Meechum.
-先生  -密查姆
- Sir... - Meechum, shh.
您還好嗎  先生
Are you all right, sir?
不怎么樣
I've been better.
我還在執勤
I'm still on duty.
有什么...
Is there...
我能做的嗎
anything I can do?
你可以出去幫我多投些票
You could go out and stuff some ballot boxes for me.
-您能緩過來的  -真能就好了
- You'll bounce back from this. - I sure hope I can.
我之前被國會警察...
Uh, when I got fired...
開除以后
from the Capitol Police...
我知道這不能相提并論  但是...
I mean, I know it doesn't compare, but...
我特別難過
I felt pretty bad.
我以為我的職業生涯終結了
I thought my career was over.
然后您扭轉了一切
Then you turned everything around.
在選舉中  沒有第二次機會
You don't get second chances in elections.
我知道
I know.
但還有很多場初選
But there's a lot of primaries ahead.
還沒有結束  您能過這一關的
All I'm saying is it's not over. You'll get through this.
-抱歉  聽起來一定很蠢  -沒有
- I'm sorry, that must sound so stupid. - No, it doesn't.
我很感激
I appreciate it.
我去外面車隊那里了  先生  有事叫我
I'll be out by the motorcade, sir, if you need anything.
謝謝  密查姆
Thank you, Meechum.
我就知道  但是不愿相信
I knew it, but I didn't wanna believe it.
只是個傷口罷了
It's only a wound.
并不致命
It's not fatal.
我的家鄉  克萊爾
My home state, Claire.
坐
Have a seat.
我終結了你的競選  所以你以牙還牙
I end your race so you end mine?
-聽我解釋  弗蘭西斯  -賭氣  報復
- Let me explain, Francis. - Spite, revenge!
坐下吧  我們得談談
Please, sit down. We need to talk.
現在生氣也沒用
Nothing is going to come from anger right now.
昨晚聊天的時候  你說這座房子是宮殿
Last night when we were talking, you called this house a palace.
這是我們開始的地方
This is where we began.
你還記得我母親差點離開了爸爸
And do you remember when my mother almost left Daddy
就因為他資助了你的競選嗎
because he funded your campaign?
她就是那么討厭你
That's how much she hated you.
但我當時不在意
But I didn't care,
因為我看到了你的潛質  我看到了未來
because I saw something. I saw a future.
我們的未來
Our future.
你開始摧毀一切之前  我們原本還有未來
We had a future until you started destroying it.
要不你不會聽的
Well, you wouldn't have listened otherwise.
我一直都聽你的
I always listen to you.
只在我說了你想聽的的時候
Only when it's what you want to hear.
好吧  克萊爾  我現在在聽
Well, all right, Claire. I'm listening now.
你有什么話這么想說
What is it you so desperately needed to say?
三十年來我們從沒輸過競選
We've never lost a race in 30 years.
我們從這里開始  所向披靡
We started here and we've always won.
你我一起
You and I, together.
但你要輸了  弗蘭西斯
But you are losing, Francis.
人們承受不起高價油
People are getting killed at the gas pumps.
《美國就業法案》不及預期
America Works is falling flat.
你的競選經理看不清現在的形勢
Your campaign manager is ten years behind ten years ago.
你沒有值得考慮的競選搭檔
You don't have a viable running mate.
我們都清楚不能是唐納德·布萊斯
We both know it can't be Donald Blythe.
當然不能
Well, of course not.
但我連名都提不上
But I have to win the goddamn nomination
還考慮什么輸贏
before I can start worrying about winning.
就算我沒這么做
Even if I hadn't done what I did,
你的競選也問題重重
your race is in real trouble.
你需要我  弗蘭西斯
You need me, Francis.
我的支持率比你高
My approvals are higher than yours.
我能幫你贏下德州
I can help you win Texas.
沒錯  所以我不希望你在達拉斯競選
Exactly. Which is why I didn't want you running in Dallas.
我需要你在我身旁
I need you at my side.
沒錯  但是以另一種方式
Yes, but in a different way.
什么方式
Different how?
我們能相互扶持  讓彼此更強  對吧
We make each other stronger, can we agree to that?
那得步調協調  但現在不是這樣
When it's working, but it's not working.
我們能協調好
We can make it work.
我們能實現當初結婚時我看到的未來
We can accomplish that future I saw when we first got married.
我們作為搭檔  真正的搭檔
It was us, as partners, real partners.
我們再一起競選吧
Let's run together, again.
不只作為夫妻
Not just as husband and wife.
你不是指...
You don't mean...
沒錯
Yes.
我很擔心你  克萊爾
I'm worried about you, Claire.
你在說瘋話  你被自負蒙蔽了
You're not making any sense. You've let your ego get in the way--
我一直都是你的競選搭檔
I've always been your running mate.
-你只是不愿承認  -當我的副總統嗎
- You just didn't wanna see it. - As my vice president?
-天啊  你知道這...  -我反復考慮過了
- Jesus. Do you have any idea--  - I've put a lot of thought into this.
你肯定沒想清楚
You can't have thought it through.
-如果你真想透徹了  -她沒經驗
- Because if you did, you'd come up - She has no experience.
-就能想到千萬個理由  -她從沒競選過
- with a million reasons-- - She's never run for anything.
無子  任人唯親  傲慢  我都考慮過了
No children, nepotism, arrogance, I've run through them all.
沒我你贏不了
You can't win without me.
我寧愿選懦弱的唐納德·布萊斯當我的副總統
I would rather have a spineless Donald Blythe as my vice president
也強過一個沒當選過公職的女人
than a woman who's never held elected office.
你要輸給一個沒當選過公職的女人了
You're losing to a woman who's never held elected office.
你不配
You don't deserve it.
你沒嘗過一無所有的滋味
You have no idea what it means to have nothing.
你不重視我們的成就
You don't value what we have achieved.
我這輩子事事都要靠自己努力爭取
I have had to fight for everything my entire life.
你知道我為什么留著這張照片嗎
Do you know why I kept this?
你知道嗎
Do you know?
因為這是我唯一一次為我父親驕傲
Because it's the one time I was proud of my father.
因為這個男人在這一刻  雖然可鄙
Because this man, in this moment, as despicable as it was,
在為生存而奮斗
is fighting to survive.
他不惜一切
He is doing whatever it took.
有沒有你  我也會這樣
And so will I, with or without you.
所以我不要跟你談下去了
So no, I will not have this conversation.
我不會再縱容你了
I will not indulge you any further.
你得放棄
You have to let this go.
我可以參與你的競選  也可以終結你的競選
I can be a part of your campaign, or I can end it.
我也會不惜一切  就像你父親那樣
I'll do whatever it takes, too. Just like your father.
但我不會放棄
But I will not let this go.
給我備輛車去格林維爾機場
I'll need a car to the Greenville Airport.
去達拉斯  沒錯
To Dallas, yes.
■
在最先舉行初選的幾個關鍵州中
南卡羅來納是黑人選民數量最多的一個州
尤其在民主黨選民中  黑人更是占有非常大的比例
在2016年2月27日剛剛結束的南卡羅來納州民主黨選舉中
出口民調顯示61%的選民為黑人
所以民主黨候選人只有贏得黑人的支持  才有可能拿下南卡
在本屆選舉的民主黨初選中
希拉里·克林頓憑借丈夫在黑人社區中多年累積的人氣和政治資本
贏得了86%的黑人選票
最終以84%對16%大勝對手佛蒙特州參議員桑德斯
■
在2016年大選中  也有候選人因與3K黨的瓜葛而制造了大新聞
臭名昭著的前3K黨頭目戴維·杜克公開號召支持共和黨候選人
紐約地產大亨唐納德·特朗普
而特朗普在接受CNN專訪時  在主持人的反復追問下  卻拒絕同3K黨劃清界限
訪談播出后  引發了一波討伐特朗普的聲浪
雖然他過了很久后終于愿意同3K黨劃清界限
但許多共和黨內的人士都認為他不適合繼續參加總統競選
在上屆大選中贏得共和黨黨內初選的前馬薩諸塞州州長米特·羅姆尼
高調發表講話  號召黨內選民不要投票給特朗普
然而共和黨選民中黑人選民數量相對來說少得多
而特朗普在共和黨初選中支持率高居不下
一定程度上是因為一些排斥移民并歧視少數裔的白人對他忠心耿耿
所以3K黨訪談事件雖然讓特朗普損失了一些粉絲
卻沒能阻止他在黨內初選中繼續領先
■
另外值得一提的是  在總統選舉中
一個共識是候選人贏得"家鄉州"是基本底線
弗蘭克輸掉了新罕布什爾  又在家門口栽了跟頭  對他影響很大
在2016年的大選中  共和黨候選人中特朗普一家獨大
幾個最有希望挑戰他的黨內候選人均面臨很大壓力
媒體認為除特朗普外的其余3名共和黨候選人
如果不能在自己的家鄉州取勝  那么將很難獲得黨內提名